Why did they curse them?
Allah says ...
They were very sinful people.
...
They went beyond the limits
of Allah.
When Allah sets a limit,
they violate it.
They were cursed.
They were sinful people
violating the limits
of Allah.
Allah says ...
At that time these people,
Bani Israel,
...
When they violated the limits
of Allah,
others who are not violating,
who saw it,
...
They will not tell them,
stop what you are doing.
What you are doing is bad.
No, they will not stop them.
They will not stop them.
...
It's a thing not to stop
evil.
You see, you have the
ability.
...
Stop it with your hand if you
are capable.
And if you are not,
...
If the individual is not
able,
because of authority, to stop
it.
...
You should speak against it
now.
And if you are still not
able,
may Allah protect us.
You should hate it with your
heart.
Hating it with your heart.
You hate that, that kind of a
thing never happened.
And that is from the weakest.
May Allah protect us.